(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
沙花叉クロヱ 卒業ライブ
Sakamata Chloe Graduation Live
沙花叉クロヱ
卒業ライブ
Sakamata Chloe
Graduation Live
どこにいても この声が
Wherever you are, I hope this voice...
君の耳に 届くように
...reaches your ears.
歌い続けるよ
I will keep on singing.
ずっとずっと
Forever and ever.
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star.
Stellar Stellar
人生リセットボタンぽちっとな
Life Reset Button, push!
最後の日まで 全力で！
With all my might until the very last day!
ごちそうさまでした！
Gochisousama deshita!
沙花叉クロヱ 卒業ライブ
Sakamata Chloe Graduation Live
ぱれぱれぱれ　輝くんだよ
Pare, Pare, Pare - it's shining
呼び合う声を合図に
With the signal of our calling voices
ぱれぱれぱれ　探しに行く
Pare, Pare, Pare - let's go search for it
スタートは何度だって
No matter how many times we start
Our Bright Parade
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Shota Horie
みんなー！今日は沙花叉の卒業ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Everyone! Thank you for coming to Sakamata's graduation live today!
精一杯頑張りますので、応援よろしくお願いします！
I'll do my absolute best, so please support me!
まだ独り言を綴った
I still wrote down my soliloquies
ただ始まりたくて走った
I ran because I just wanted to begin
遠く暗がりに灯った
Lit up in the distant darkness
それは眩しすぎた名前
That name was far too bright
それは優しすぎる思い出
Those memories are far too kind
もっと近づけと手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand to get closer
思いがけず結び合った
Unexpectedly, we were tied together
ほら今前...
Look, now in front...
Our Bright Parade
今日は ほら 笑顔さ
Today, see, I'm smiling
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, I'm going to shine
悔しさも愛おしさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love along
駆け抜け羽ばたけ 飛び出すのさ
Run through, spread your wings, and fly out
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき日差し
A modest prayer is the light, an endless sunshine
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
Finding you is something I can be proud of
ここから これから Our Bright Parade
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade
まだ 頼りない予感を
Still, a faint premonition
歌おう 恥ずかしくなってないよ
Let's sing it, I'm not embarrassed
誰も解けないイマジナリー
An imaginary world no one can solve
いつか また会えるおまじない
A spell so we can meet again someday
あの日 ゼロに始まったストーリー
A story that started from zero that day
数えきれない言の葉 数えるような思いじゃないさ
Uncountable words, it's not a feeling you can count
ほら 今 僕ら ひとつと呼ぼう
Look, now, let's call ourselves one
パレパレパレ 美しいんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, it's beautiful
許しあえる切な夜は 煌めく
The painful nights where we can forgive each other sparkle
パレパレパレ また遠い空
Pare-pare-pare, once again the distant sky
相応しい旅路とは 君と歩くことさ
The right journey is walking with you
君と歩くことなんだ
Walking with you
「ただいま」を聞けば 「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
If I hear 'I'm home', I'll shout 'Welcome back'
当たり前じゃないから
Because it's not something to take for granted
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, I'm going to shine
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
Filling the darkness is you, it's me
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare-pare-pare, I'm going to shine
悔しさも愛おしさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love along
駆け抜け羽ばたけ 飛び出すのさ
Run through, spread your wings, and fly out
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき日差し
A modest prayer is the light, an endless sunshine
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵のスタートさ
Jumping in with you is a wonderful start
ここから これから Our Bright Parade
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade
Our Bright Parade
あのバンド
Ano Band
あのバンドの歌は私に
The songs of that band...
わかっていたけど響く 笑い声聞こえる
...to me, I knew it, they resonate, I can hear the laughter
あのバンドの歌は私には
The songs of that band, to me...
つんざく 踏切の音みたい
...they're piercing, like the sound of a railroad crossing
背中を 押すなよ
Don't push my back
もうそこに 電車が来る
The train is coming there already
目を閉じる
I close my eyes
暗闇に差す 後光
A halo shining in the darkness
耳塞ぐ
I cover my ears
確かに刻む 鼓動
The heartbeat surely ticking
胸の奥
Deep in my chest
身を震わす 心臓
My heart is trembling
他に何も 聞きたくない 私が放つ 音以外
I don't want to hear anything else, except for the sound I release
虚像に 居場所探したり
Searching for a place in false images
悲しい歌に 救われていたんだけど
I was saved by sad songs, but...
あのバンドの歌が誰かには
The songs of that band, for someone...
私だけが 間違いばかりみたい
It's like only I am full of mistakes
目を閉じる
I close my eyes
暗闇に差す 後光
A halo shining in the darkness
耳塞ぐ
I cover my ears
確かに刻む 鼓動
The heartbeat surely ticking
胸の奥
Deep in my chest
身を揺らす 心臓
My heart is trembling
心臓
Heart
ほかに何も聞きたくない
I don't want to hear anything else
わたしが放つ音以外
Except for the sounds I make
いらない
I don't need it
背中を
My back
押すなよ
Don't push me
さあ、地獄の底まで触るな
Come, don't touch me until the depths of hell
始発の
The first train's
ベルが鳴る
The bell rings
乗客はわたし一人だけ
I'm the only passenger
手を叩く
Clapping hands
わたしだけの音
Only my sound
足鳴らす
Stomping feet
即席残すまで
Until leaving an improvised footprint
目を開ける
Opening eyes
孤独の衝動を
The impulse of loneliness
受け止める
Accepting it
心の衝動を今胸の奥
The impulse of the heart, now deep within my chest
確かめる心音
Confirming the heartbeat
ほかに何も聞きたくない
I don't want to hear anything else
わたしが放つ音以外
Except for the sounds I make
ごちそうさまでした
Thank you for the meal (Gochisousama deshita)
ビターチョコデコレーション
作詞・作曲：syudou
Bitter Choco Decoration
Lyrics/Composition: syudou
人に信じないように愛さないように期待しないように
Try not to believe, not to love, not to expect from people
かといって角が立たないように気取らないように目立たぬように
But also try not to cause friction, not to be pretentious, not to stand out
誰一人傷つけぬように虐めぬように零さぬように
Don't hurt anyone, don't bully, don't spill anything
かといって善がバレぬように威張らぬように
But don't let your kindness be found out, don't be arrogant
感情を殺しリップサービスも忘れぬように
Kill your emotions and don't forget the lip service
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
Always laugh and spread your charm
ビターチョコデコレーション 兎角言わずに堪能召し上がれ
Bitter choco decoration, don't say much and enjoy eating it
ビターチョコデコレーション 食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなきゃ
Bitter choco decoration, you must fix your pickiness
頭空っぽその後に 残る心が本物なら
If what's left after your head is empty is your real heart
きっと君だって同じこと
Then surely it's the same for you
ところで一つ伺いますが先日どこかでやった嫌
By the way, I have a question: that nasty thing you did the other day...
無駄に自我を晒さないように話さないように分からないように
Try not to expose your ego needlessly, not to speak, not to be understood
黙りなさい口を閉ざさないように笑わすより笑われるように
Be quiet, but don't close your mouth; be laughed at rather than making people laugh
人をちゃんと敬うように馬鹿目なように称えるように
Respect people properly, act foolish, and praise them
でも決して病みにならぬようにふざけぬように
But never become dark, and don't fool around
集団さんからの終身刑 またへこらへこら言っちゃって
Life sentence from the collective, saying "yes, yes" again
前髪上等最強じゃん とかどうでもいいのに言っちゃって
Saying "Your bangs are great, you're the best" even though you don't care
毎朝毎晩限界集教的社会の集団に
Every morning and every night, in a group of borderline religious society
決して発表しないように
Try never to announce it
ビターチョコデコレーション 時に孤独な愛は君を汚す
Bitter choco decoration, sometimes lonely love stains you
ビターチョコデコレーション 去る鳥の跡きっとクソの跡
Bitter choco decoration, the tracks of a departing bird are surely tracks of shit
初めはあんなに凄そうな 大言壮語並べたが
At first, such grand words were lined up
いややいやよも好きのうち
Saying no is also a sign of liking it
いやはやしかし今日が初めてでこんなドアな秘めセンスあるよ
Well, well, but today is the first time, and you have such a secret sense...
恋する季節にビターチョコデコレーション
In the season of love, bitter choco decoration
恋する気持ちでビターチョコデコレーション
With feelings of love, bitter choco decoration
F-U-C-K-Y-O-U
ビターチョコデコレーション 皆が望む理想に憧れて
Bitter choco decoration, longing for the ideal everyone wants
ビターチョコデコレーション 個性や情は全部焼き払い
Bitter choco decoration, burning away all individuality and emotion
ビターチョコデコレーション 欲やエゴは殺して土に埋め
Bitter choco decoration, kill the desires and ego and bury them in the dirt
ビターチョコデコレーション 僕は大人にやっと成ったよママ
Bitter choco decoration, I finally became an adult, Mama
明日のこともその先も
About tomorrow and beyond
地獄は続くどこまでも
Hell continues everywhere
おだからこか今だけは子供のままで
So for now, stay as a child
いい子はもちろん　ままごと一生
後回しにやってこうぜ
Good kids, of course, play house for a lifetime.
Let's put it off and get going.
ああ、思い出した　あんたの時の
生真面目そうな...
Ah, I remember... you looked so serious
back then...
やっぱいいや
Never mind.
笑ってるけど　どこか泣いてんだ
痛みはご褒美の日な
Laughing but crying somewhere.
Pain is the reward day.
思ってるけど　ずっと溜めてんだ
いつの味　呪いのアイが
Thinking it, but always bottling it up.
What flavor is it? This cursed love...
擦り減って濁って　アイラブ自分
...worn down and muddied. I love myself.
さてそうやって　こもって不干渉
Now, hiding away like that, non-interference.
大きな声　少ししてみるけど
I try to make a loud noise.
乾いた傘　痛いってなるんだ
But a dry umbrella just ends up hurting.
わがままに選んではポイして
Selfishly picking and tossing away.
理屈抜きで夢とか信じたい
I want to believe in dreams without any logic.
劣等でどうかしちゃ
マリオネットなんかじゃない
If I'm inferior, so what?
I'm not some marionette.
擬態ごっこいいよもっと
Mimicry is fine, give me more.
つまんない朝よりのシンデレラ
Cinderella from a boring morning.
叶えたい　消えたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's warping.
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解で
They're all correct.
どれも正解だった
They were all correct.
叶えたい　消えたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's warping.
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself.
君だけに教えてもいいか
Can I tell only you?
Brain in the world of myself
to myself isolated cycle
I'm go where I don't go
or maybe I chose not to know
光って出ちゃって　I hate 自分
Shining and coming out, I hate myself.
避難って壊した　ポンコツの才能
Called it refuge and broke it, a piece of junk talent.
また隠しちゃって　後悔して
Hiding it again and regretting it.
変わったつもりが　嫌ってなるんだ
Thought I changed, but I end up hating it.
うざいうざい愛　不信感次第
Annoying, annoying love, depends on the distrust.
糸切ってそろそろ　息したい
Cut the strings, I want to breathe soon.
劣等でどうかしちゃ
マリオネットなんかじゃない
If I'm inferior, so what?
I'm not some marionette.
嫌いなんだったか　言ってたんだ
I was saying I hated it.
足掻いてみたって　本音は死んでいた
No matter how much I struggled, my true feelings were dead.
選びたい　捨てたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to choose, I want to throw away, it's warping.
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解で
They're all correct.
どれも正解だった
They were all correct.
選びたい　捨てたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to choose, I want to throw away, it's warping.
マリオネットだから
Because I'm a marionette.
擬態ごっこいいよもっと
Mimicry is fine, give me more.
つまんない朝よりのシンデレラ
Cinderella from a boring morning.
叶えたい　消えたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's warping.
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解で
They're all correct.
どれも正解だった
They were all correct.
叶えたい　消えたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want it to come true, I want to disappear, it's warping.
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself.
どれも正解で
They're all correct.
どれも正解だった
They were all correct.
選びたい　捨てたい　歪んでいくんだ
I want to choose, I want to throw away, it's warping.
僕と僕との境界線
The boundary line between me and myself.
君だけに教えてもいいか
Can I tell only you?
で、それすらもう　どうでもいいか
And even that doesn't matter anymore.
はい！ということで！
Yes! And so!
バクバクバクーン！秘密結社holoXの掃除屋、
インターンシャチの沙花叉クロヱです！いただきまーす！
Baku-baku-bakoon! Cleaner of Secret Society holoX,
intern orca Sakamata Chloe here! Itadakimasu!
はい、えー今日は沙花叉の卒業ライブに来てくださり、
本当にありがとうございます！
Yes, uh, thank you all so much for coming
to Sakamata's graduation live today!
えー、ハッシュタグ、こちらの沙花叉クロヱ卒業ライブで
ぜひ感想をつぶやいてもらえると嬉しいです！
Uh, the hashtag is #沙花叉クロヱ卒業ライブ,
I'd be happy if you could tweet your thoughts there!
そしてもうすでにトレンド1位ということで、
ありがとうございます！みんなありがとう！
And apparently it's already trending at number 1,
so thank you! Thank you everyone!
はい、ということで、えー「オーバーブライトパレード」、
「あのバンド」、「ビターチョコデコレーション」、「擬態ごっこ」と歌わせていただきました。
Yes, and so, I sang "Overbright Parade", "Ano Bando",
"Bitter Choco Decoration", and "Gitai Gokko".
「あのバンド」ではすいせい先輩とぺこら先輩に
ゲストに来ていただいて...
For "Ano Bando", Suisei-senpai and Pekora-senpai
came as guests...
「ビターチョコデコレーション」では「かな研」のお二人に
来ていただきました！ありがとうございました！
For "Bitter Choco Decoration", the two from "Kanade Kan"
came! Thank you very much!
ちょっとどちらもね、違ったテイストではあると思うんですが、
すごくかっこいい曲だったんじゃないでしょうか。
They both have different tastes, but I think
they were really cool songs, weren't they?
どうでした？いい感じだった？
ね、いい感じだったよね！
How were they? Good?
Yeah, they were good, right!
よかったらね、そちらのたくさん愛も
つぶやいてください。よろしくお願いします！
If you'd like, please tweet lots of love for them too.
Thank you!
そして、えー沙花叉のソロ曲ですね、「オーバーブライトパレード」と
「擬態ごっこ」、どちらも生で歌わせていただいております。
And, uh, Sakamata's solo songs, "Overbright Parade" and
"Gitai Gokko", I'm singing both of them live.
緊張しすぎて声が出ません！
もう助けてください！
I'm so nervous my voice won't come out!
Someone help me!
なんかもう無理かもしんない、本当に！
見守って...
I feel like I might not be able to do this, seriously!
Please watch over...
ちょっと応援よろしくお願いします。お願いお願いお願い。
マジで超緊張してるんで。よろしくお願いします！
Please give me some support. Please, please, please.
I'm really super nervous. Thank you!
お、え、YAGOOからなんかビデオレターが来てるって？
はい、じゃあ見ます！よろしくお願いします！
Oh, uh, a video letter from YAGOO?
Okay, let's watch it! Go ahead!
クロヱさん、また配信をご覧のみなさん、こんばんは。
Chloe-san, and everyone watching the stream,
good evening.
カバー株式会社代表取締役の谷郷元昭です。
I'm Motoaki Tanigo, CEO of Cover Corp.
こんばんは！白いですね。
Good evening! You're so white.
そうですね。クロヱさん、あの...
Indeed. Chloe-san, well...
最初の印象としては初配信であの、見てですね、
As for my first impression, I watched your debut stream...
まあ、いい意味でアクが強くて、
And, in a good way, you had a strong personality...
まあこのタレントさん、すごく人気になるだろうなというふうに、あの、感じていました。
I felt that this talent would surely become very popular.
ほいー。あははは。
Hoi. Hahaha.
また、そうですね、印象に残っている活動内容としては、
Also, well, as for activities that left an impression on me...
まあ、生放送で、周年配信での、
Well, in the live broadcast, during your anniversary stream...
あの、まあ歌のパフォーマンスだったと思うんですけれども、
I believe it was your singing performance...
非常に緊張感が、こちらにも伝わってくるような感じで、
I could really feel the tension even from here...
まあドキドキしながら見守っていたのを覚えて、
I remember watching over you with a pounding heart...
見守れー。社長！
Watch over me! CEO!
また、かなたさんとか、すいせいさんのような、あの先輩と絡まれている中で、
Also, while you collaborated with seniors like Kanata-san or Suisei-san...
こう自信を深めながら歌のパフォーマンスが上がっていくのを感じていて、
I felt your singing performance improving as you gained confidence...
非常に感動したのを、あの、今でも覚えています。
I still remember being very moved by it.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい。あの最後になりますが、
Yes. Lastly...
あの三年間、あの活動、本当に長い間お疲れ様でした。
Thank you very much for your hard work over these three years of activity.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
真面目！
So serious!
私からは以上になります。ありがとうございました。
That's all from me. Thank you.
あー、ありがとうございましたー！
Ah, thank you very much!
いや、ありがたいですね。成長を YAGOO に見守ってもらっていたということで、
Wow, I'm so grateful. Hearing that YAGOO was watching over my growth...
とってもとっても嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
I'm very, very happy. Thank you.
はい。ということで、じゃあそろそろ次の曲に移りたいと思うんですが、
All right. Well then, it's about time to move on to the next song...
ちょっとお水飲んでもいいすか？ごめんなさい。
But, can I drink some water? Sorry.
（水のごくごく音）
(Gulping water sounds)
次の曲に行きたいと思うんですが、
I want to go to the next song, but...
次の曲は初期の頃に歌ってみたを投稿した、
The next song is that one I posted a cover of in my early days...
あの曲です！わかる人いる？
That's the song! Anyone know it?
ちょっと当ててみて、今。
Try to guess it now.
わかる？なかなか、あーでもどうなんだろう、印象に残ってくれてるかな？
Do you know? I wonder, well, I hope it left an impression?
どうでしょう。まだね、お水飲んでるとこなんだよね。
What do you think? I'm still drinking water, though.
まだ水飲んで欲しそう、みんな。あはは。
Everyone seems to want me to drink more water. Haha.
ありがとう。いっぱいお水飲んで元気入れたよ。大丈夫だよ、ありがとに。
Thank you. I drank plenty of water and got energized. I'm fine, thanks.
おって言ってる。あ、来るよ、そろそろ。お、お、え、あ、え、
You're saying "Oh". Ah, here it comes. Oh, oh, eh, ah, eh...
フクロウ？アニマル？違う。
Owl? Animal? No.
キャットラビング？違う。
Cat Loving? No.
そう、答え出ました。
That's right, the answer is out.
そこの君！正解です。
You there! You're correct.
次の曲は偽物人間40号です。
The next song is "Fake Person 40".
それでは聴いてください、偽物人間40号。
Please listen to it: "Fake Person 40".
メーデー、メーデー 嫌になるわホントさ
Mayday, mayday, I'm really getting sick of this.
まだジャンキージャンキーのまんまで
I'm still just a junkie, junkie.
ホントに叶わないんだって分かってる
I know it's really not going to come true.
あぁ 散々転げ回って足掻いてる
Ah, I'm struggling, rolling around endlessly.
ほらやっぱりやっぱりつまんない
See, as expected, as expected, it's boring.
番に執着に寄り添って
Clinging to obsession one after another.
機械みたいに動いている
Moving like a machine.
あぁ 知ってる知ってる 使い古された言葉使ってみたって
Ah, I know, I know. Even if I try to use worn-out words...
あの人のようにはなれないのです
I can't become like that person.
戯言と至極真っ当 刺されどいた日々だ
I've been pierced by nonsense and common sense in those moved-aside days.
所詮僕は偽物さ 壊れる前に
In the end, I'm a fake. Before I break...
壊してしまう前に
Before you break me.
糞が！
Shit!
メーデー、メーデー 嫌になるわホントさ
Mayday, mayday, I'm really getting sick of this.
まだジャンキージャンキーだ もう飽き飽きなんだ
I'm still a junkie, junkie. I'm already sick and tired of it.
メーデー、メーデー ゴミ溜めへ向かうような
Mayday, mayday, like heading for a garbage dump...
ファンキー、ファンキー人間なんで
I'm a funky, funky person.
愚かな人造人間なんで
I'm a foolish android.
あぁ 曖昧な自分のことは嫌いだし
Ah, I hate my vague self...
あぁ あんたには分からないんだって思ってる
Ah, I think that you wouldn't understand.
ほらやっぱりやっぱりつまんない
See, as expected, as expected, it's boring.
燦々と輝くはずだった
It was supposed to shine brilliantly.
あの日描いた未来はここ無い
The future I envisioned that day isn't here.
絶え間なく流れ込んだ 忘れたい過去が
The past I want to forget has flowed in ceaselessly.
漏れ出すオイル事情
Leaking oil situation.
偽物人間40号
Junky Night Town
狂うフラット
Going mad, flat
抜いて終わらせてしまおうか
Should I pull it out and end it?
メーデーメーデー 疲れたよ 本当さ
Mayday, mayday, I'm tired, for real
メーデーメーデー 嫌になるわ 本当さ
Mayday, mayday, I'm sick of it, for real
まだジャンキージャンキーなまんまで
Still being a junkie, junkie
メーデーメーデー 誰か助けてください
Mayday, mayday, someone please help me
メーデーメーデー 足ひとつ出せずに
Mayday, mayday, without taking a single step
またジャンキージャンキーだ もう飽き飽きなんだ
A junkie again, I'm so fed up with it
メーデーメーデー 自分さえ守れない
Mayday, mayday, I can't even protect myself
ようなファンキーファンキー人間なんで
Like the funky, funky human I am
ああ ジャンキージャンキージャンキー
Ah, junkie junkie junkie
ジャンキー人間なんで
junkie human after all
あぁ クソが
Ah, damn it
コネクト
Connect
作詞・作曲：渡辺翔
Lyrics & Composition: Sho Watanabe
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to make sure
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the closing darkness and move forward
いつになったらなくした未来を 私ここでまた見ることできるの
When will I be able to see the lost future here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を 何度でも裂いてこの世界歩んでいこう
I'll tear through the overflowing shadows of anxiety and walk this world
とめどなく刻まれた時は今始まりを告げ
The endlessly carved time now signals the beginning
変わらない思いをのせ 閉ざされた扉開けよう
Carrying unchanging feelings, let's open the closed door
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart started running to paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても 空は
Even if I stop on a difficult path, the sky...
綺麗な青さでいつも待っててくれるから怖くない
...is always waiting with a beautiful blue, so I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't give up
振り返れば仲間がいて 気がつけば優しく包まれていた
Looking back, there were friends, and before I knew it, I was gently enveloped
何もかもが歪んだ世界で 唯一信じれるここが救いだった
In a world where everything was distorted, this place, the only one I could believe in, was my salvation
喜びも悲しみも分かち合えば強まる思い
Sharing both joy and sorrow strengthens our feelings
この声が届くのなら きっと奇跡は起こせるだろう
If this voice reaches, I'm sure a miracle can happen
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to make sure
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the closing darkness and move forward
どんなに大きな壁があっても 越えてみせるからきっと
No matter how big the wall is, I'll show you I can overcome it
明日を信じて祈って
Believe in tomorrow and pray
壊れた世界で彷徨って私は
In this broken world, I'm wandering, and I...
引き寄せられるように辿り着いた
...arrived as if drawn toward you
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来を描くため
My awakened heart started running to paint the future
難しい道で立ち止まっても 空は
Even if I stop on a difficult path, the sky...
綺麗な青さでいつも待っててくれるから怖くない
...is always waiting with a beautiful blue, so I'm not afraid
いつも待っててくれるから怖くない
Because you're always waiting for me, I'm not afraid
もう何があっても挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't be discouraged
ずっと明日を待って
Waiting for tomorrow forever
メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット
作詞・作曲：かいりきベア 編曲：すりぃ
Mage of Violet
Lyrics/Composition: Kairiki Bear Arrangement: Three
暗い本ばかり見てないで
Stop looking only at dark books
ウラパパパパラリラ踊れよ
Urapapapapararira, dance!
魔界学校の優等生
The top student of the demon world school
華やかなワガママ称えよう
Let's praise the flashy selfishness
いないいないばあでこっち向いて
Peek-a-boo, look this way
したたかな未来を咲かせよう
Let's make a resilient future bloom
次第曖昧ぶっ高まって
Gradually, it becomes ambiguous and intense
溜まったパワハラで黒魔術
Dark magic from accumulated power harassment
聖の刻印に集えよ
Gather at the holy mark
闇に震え凍えるベロス
Belos shivering and freezing in the dark
刹那に響く言葉は
The words that echo in an instant
打ち切り発狂パラダイス
Discontinued madness paradise
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
これからも私の元で
Stay by my side from now on as well
不思議な力撃ち放って
Fire off a mysterious power
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
And the whole world will smile
ウラパパパパラリラ歌えば
If we sing Urapapapapararira
一生一生だよね
It's for a lifetime, right?
クライモード走してないで
Don't be running in cry mode
なまぬる体さらば踊れよ
Farewell to lukewarm bodies, dance!
視界以外見逸らさないで
Don't look away from anything but your vision
今はただ離れて行かないで
For now, just don't go far away
ヤイヤイ待ってあっち向いて
Hey hey, wait, look over there
今はまだ心の準備を
I'm still preparing my heart
期待遮って固まって
Blocking expectations and freezing up
ウラパパパ動け黒魔術
Urapapapa, move, black magic!
我に続け今宵の
Follow me, tonight's
闇を破れ召し上がれよ
Break the darkness, please enjoy
討つべきものその名は
The thing to be struck down, its name is
眠りの八唱パラダイス
Sleeping eight-chant paradise
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
白黒つけてあげるから
Because I'll make things clear
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandishing a mysterious power
皆で笑顔になっちゃって
Everyone will smile together
ウラパパパパラリラ歌えば
If we sing Urapapapapararira
一生一生だもんね
It's for a lifetime, isn't it?
ヒラリヒラリと紫に染まって
Fluttering and fluttering, dyed in purple
これからもあなたの元で
Stay by your side from now on as well
奇跡の呪文解き放って
Release the spell of miracles
咲かせる笑顔の花を
The flowers of smiles that will bloom
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
これからも変わらないままで
Staying unchanged from now on as well
不思議な力ほら宿って
See, a mysterious power dwells within
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
And the whole world will smile
ウラパパパパラリラ歌えば
If we sing Urapapapapararira
一生一生だよね
It's for a lifetime, right?
絶対一生だよね
Definitely for a lifetime, right?
はい！ということでメイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレットでしたー！ありがとう！
Yes! So that was Mage of Violet! Thank you!
シオン先輩も来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much Shion-senpai for coming!
嬉しい！ありがとう！呼んでくれて！
I'm so happy! Thank you for inviting me!
いや、本当にね、シオン先輩がちゃんと沙花叉のこの卒業ライブに、来てくれて、こんなに愛を示してくれるなんて...
No, really, for Shion-senpai to come to my graduation live and show me this much love...
本当に！最高です！それだけでですか？えっ？違ったんですか？
Really! It's the best! Just for that? Eh? Was it something else?
いやいやいやいや、いやいやいや、言って、最後まで言って
No no no no, no no no, say it, say it to the end
いや、ねー、うん、はい、そう、そうそうそう、うん
Well, yeah, yes, right, right right right, yeah
あい、あい、あーい、あーい、あーい、あーい！
Ai, ai, ai, ai, ai, ai!
あーい！あーい！あーい！だよ！びっくりした、はいはいはいみたいな感じ。あーい！あーい！あーい！あーい！ああ、なんか良かった。
Ai! Ai! Ai! That's it! You surprised me, I thought you were saying "yes yes yes". Ai! Ai! Ai! Ai! Ah, that was good.
でもねー
But you know...
シオン先輩とはさ、
Since I joined Hololive,
ホロライブに入ってからめちゃめちゃ仲良くなりましたよね！
we've become really close, Shion-senpai!
なった！
We have!
ねえ！そうだよな！
Yeah! That's right!
いろんな場所も行ったしね。
We went to so many places too.
いや、本当にいろんな場所行った。
Yeah, we really went everywhere.
ねえ、ロケも行ったしね。
And we did those on-site shoots too.
行った！
We did!
水族館もね。
The aquarium, too.
行った！
We went there!
愛の告白も受けてくれたし。
And you even accepted my confession of love.
あれ？記憶がない。
Huh? I don't remember that.
あった！あった！あったの！
It happened! It did! It really happened!
そうだよね、覚えてるよ。
Right, right, I remember now.
配信でもいろんなことしたよね。
We did so many things on stream too.
いろんなことして、いろんなこと喋ったね。
We did so much and talked about so much.
森も行ったしね。
We even went to the forest.
森行ったね。クリスマスの森ね。
We did go to the forest. That Christmas forest.
いやー楽しかった。本当に。
Man, that was so much fun. Really.
本当に楽しかった。ありがとう。
It really was fun. Thank you.
卒業した後も、仲良くしてください。
Please keep being my friend even after I graduate.
どうしようかなー。
Hmm, I don't know...
えー！嘘！
What?! No way!
もう帰っちゃおうかな、今日。
Maybe I should just go home today.
ダメだよ！ダメだって！
No! You can't! Don't say that!
もう、どうでもよくなっちゃった。
Aww, now I'm feeling all down.
嘘だよ嘘！当たり前でしょ！
I'm kidding, I'm kidding! Of course we will!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
言わなくてもわかるでしょ。
You should know that without me saying it.
本当に帰るなんて言われたら大変なことになるところだった。
I thought it was going to be a disaster when you said you'd leave.
そう、いろんな思い出積み上げてきたんですけど...
Right, we've built up so many memories together...
沙花叉的には、まだまだ、
But for me, I still want to
思い出作りたいなーなんて思ったりなんかして。
make even more memories with you.
おお。
Oh?
ちょっと今日は、せっかくホロライブで過ごせる
Since today is the last time
最後の時間だと思うので、おねだりしちゃおうかなー。
I'll be in Hololive, I have some favors to ask.
断れないよね。
I can't really say no, can I?
はい、聞いてくれますよね？
Exactly. You'll listen, right?
はい、はい。卒業しますからね。
Yes, yes. Since you're graduating and all.
断れないやつだ、これ。
This is one of those 'un-refusable' situations.
「はい」と「うん」以外存在してないんだな。
So 'Yes' and 'Okay' are my only options, huh?
よかったー！OK！
Yay! Okay!
しょうがないよね。
It can't be helped, right?
じゃあ、まずは、あんまりちゃんと答えてくれなかったり、
Well, first of all... since you always
はぐらかされたりするので...
dodge the question or give me vague answers...
沙花叉に「大好き」を伝えてほしいです！
I want you to tell me 'I love you'!
「大好き」を伝えてほしいです！
I want you to say 'I love you'!
言って！言ってよ！
Say it! Come on, say it!
わかった、わかった。
Alright, alright.
「まずは」って何？一つ目ってこと？
Wait, 'first of all'? So this is just the first one?
よく気づきましたね。
Good catch!
バレないと思ったから言ったんだけど。
I thought I could sneak that past you.
沙花叉、大好きだよ。
Chloe, I love you.
やったー！
Yay!
今日めっちゃ頑張れそう！やったー！
Now I feel like I can give it my all today! Yay!
じゃあ、ちょっと「よしよし」してほしいなー。
Next, I want you to give me a head pat.
え、これは「次は」ってこと？
Wait, so this is 'the next one'?
そうですよ。タスク2。
Exactly. Task 2.
よしよし。
There, there.
やったー！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
えらいねー。
You're a good girl.
じゃあ...
And then...
シオン先輩の犬になりたいから、
I want to be Shion-senpai's dog,
沙花叉のことワンちゃんみたいな感じで「よしよし」してほしいなって。
so please pat me like I'm your little puppy.
これ、本当に卒業ライブだよね？
Are you sure this is a graduation live?
プライドとかないの？
Don't you have any pride?
アイドルとしての... ねえ！
As an idol... Hey!
ワンワン！よしよし！嬉しい！
Woof woof! Head pats! I'm so happy!
可愛いワンちゃんだね。
What a cute little puppy.
じゃあ、そのついでにちょっと蹴ってもらっていいですか？
Then, while you're at it, could you kick me?
ちょっと待って。本当にこれ大丈夫？
Wait a minute. Is this really okay?
大丈夫です。最後に夢叶えさせてください。
It's fine. Please let my dream come true at the end.
えいっ。
There!
もっと！強く！もっと！
More! Harder! More!
人を蹴ったことないんですけど。えいっ。
I've never kicked a person before... Take that!
最高でしたー！やったー！
That was the best! Yay!
最高って...。
The best? Seriously?
シオン先輩、これからも仲良くしてくださいね。
Shion-senpai, let's keep being close friends.
えっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait...
どうしたんですか？どうしたんですか？
What's wrong? What's wrong?
いや、嬉しいな。こうやって一緒に過ごせてね。
No, I'm just happy. Being able to spend time together like this.
ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ...
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait...
ねー、嬉しいなー。
Yeah, I'm happy.
嬉しい、嬉しい。
Happy, happy.
これからもずっと一緒にいようね。
Let's be together forever from now on.
うん。何、何、何？ずっと一緒、うん。
Yeah. What, what, what? Together forever, yeah.
うん、ずっと一緒にいようね。
Yeah, let's be together forever.
そうだよ、いやー、ね！
That's right, yeah!
ね！
Yeah!
影、これ？影？影かな？
A shadow, is this? A shadow? Maybe a shadow?
なんか、後ろからずっと付いてくる。影かと思った。
It's been following me from behind. I thought it was a shadow.
え、これ、これだったの？
Eh, it was this?
いや、そうですよ。
Yeah, it was.
あ、今叶ったんだ、じゃあ。
Ah, so it's come true now.
叶いました！ありがとうございます、本当に。
It has! Thank you so much, really.
よかった。
I'm glad.
お、危なかった。この中だったら帰ってたもんね、坂又。
Oh, that was close. You would have gone home if it were like this, Sakamata.
そうですよ、そうですよ。
That's right, that's right.
危なかった、危なかった。総帥のおかげでね。
That was close, close. Thanks to the Leader.
この先も卒業ライブができるということで、続くってことですね。
That we can continue with the graduation live from here on.
そうです！
That's right!
わー、よかった。じゃあ、まあ、言ったら...
Wow, I'm glad. So, well, if you say so...
世界救ったみたいなもんか、じゃあ。
It's like I saved the world then.
そうです！
That's right!
そうだよね。うん。
Right. Yeah.
このあとも頑張りますから。
I'll keep doing my best after this.
頑張ってね。それは、それは頑張ってね。
Do your best. Definitely do your best.
えー、衝撃、衝撃的だった。忘れられないな、忘れられない。
Eh, it was shocking, shocking. I won't forget it, I won't forget.
忘れられない経験、忘れられない思い出になった。
It's become an unforgettable experience, an unforgettable memory.
やったー！衝撃！
Yay! Shocking!
よかった。本当にもう衝撃的だった。でも、ありがとうございました。
I'm glad. It was truly shocking. But thank you very much.
いえ、こちらこそありがとうございました。
No, thank YOU very much.
ね、また今度遊ぼうね。言ってたやつね、ね、言ってたやつ。
Hey, let's play again next time. The one we talked about, yeah.
うん。行こう、行こう。
Yeah. Let's go, let's go.
はい！頑張ってね、坂又！
Okay! Do your best, Sakamata!
はい！ありがとう！ありがとう！バイバイ！
Yes! Thank you! Thank you! Bye bye!
あー、最高だった。軽蔑もされたかったんだけどね。最高。
Ah, that was the best. I wanted to be looked down on too, though. The best.
じゃ、ということで、次の曲頑張りたいと思います。
Well, with that, I'd like to do my best on the next song.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
そこに跪け！
Kneel right there!
吐き捨てたような現実は
A reality that seems spat out
一刀両断 叩き斬れ！
Cut it down with a single stroke!
終わりなき輪廻に迷いし子等よ
Children lost in the endless cycle of reincarnation
漆黒の翼で誘わん
I shall invite you with jet-black wings
我ら、エデンの星を統べる者
We, the rulers of the planet Eden
秘密結社 HoloX！天下御免！
Secret Society HoloX! Peerless under the heavens!
常夜リペイント
Tokoyami Paint
作詞・作曲・編曲：yuzen (Hifumi,inc.)
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: yuzen (Hifumi,inc.)
反吐 出るほど どうしようもないこの世界
This world, so hopeless it makes me want to vomit
どうして欲しい？
What do you want me to do?
馬鹿げた 終末告げる鐘が鳴る
Stupidly, the bell announcing the end is ringing
Rat-tat-tat 踊ろうぜ Tripしようぜ
Rat-tat-tat, let's dance, let's trip
陰キャも 陽キャも Sing a song
Introverts and extroverts alike, sing a song
気持ちいいことだけがすべて
Pleasurable things are everything
墜ちていく 闇の底へ
Falling to the bottom of the darkness
甘い甘いメロディ
A sweet, sweet melody
ほらどうぞどうぞ 手の鳴る方へ
Come this way, this way, towards the clapping hands
もう逃げられない
You can't escape anymore
ほら 闇に染まれば
Look, if you're dyed in darkness
世界を塗り替えろ
Repaint the world
望めば連れてやろう すべて
If you wish, I'll take it all
常識 破り捨てろ
Throw away common sense
屈服し 射抜かせ 火をつけろ
Yield, let me shoot through you, set it on fire
Rat-tat-tat-tat-tat
すべてを喰らい尽くせ
Devour everything
Rat-tat-tat-tat-tat
機密を教えてやろう
I'll let you in on the secret
悪のカリスマ 導くぞ 民草
The charisma of evil, I shall lead the common people
正義とか知らないし 地均して誘い
I don't know about justice, I'll level the ground and invite you
真面目に不真面目 平謝り 糠雨
Seriously unserious, profuse apologies, a drizzling rain
望み求め願い叶え 世界征服
Wishing, seeking, dreams coming true, world domination
Rat-tat-tat-tat 踊ろうぜ Swingしようぜ
Rat-tat-tat-tat, let's dance, let's swing
退屈な世界へ Bye-bye-bye
Bye-bye-bye to the boring world
醒めることのない夢を見せる
I'll show you a dream you'll never wake up from
ほら お眠りなさい
Now, go to sleep
もっともっと奥へ
Further and further inside
ほらどうぞどうぞ 息絶えたいでしょう
Come now, come now, you want to stop breathing, don't you?
もうやめられない
You can't stop anymore
ほら 悪に染まれば
Look, if you're dyed in evil
世界を塗り替えろ
Repaint the world
まどろみを与えよう すべて
I'll give you a slumber, for everything
ルールを書き換えろ
Rewrite the rules
くるくる回し尽くせ 焼き尽くせ
Keep spinning it around, burn it all up
Rat-tat-tat-tat-tat
すべての紛い物へ
To all the shams
Rat-tat-tat-tat-tat
機密を教えてやろう
I'll let you in on the secret
機は熟した。
The time has come.
狂気の宴の始まりだ！
The banquet of madness begins!
貴様ら、準備はいいか！
Are you bastards ready!
括目せよ！
Pay close attention!
クロヱ！クロヱ！手上げろ！手上げろ！
Chloe! Chloe! Hands up! Hands up!
いろは！いろは！叫ぶでござる！
Iroha! Iroha! Shout it out!
こより！こより！踊っちゃえ！踊っちゃえ！
Koyori! Koyori! Let's dance! Let's dance!
ホロックス！
HoloX!
世界を手にするホロックス！
HoloX that will take over the world!
ルイ姉！ルイ姉！
Lui-nee! Lui-nee!
もっと！もっと！
More! More!
ラプラス！ラプラス！
La+! La+!
最後は全員行くぞ！
Everyone together at the end!
ホロックス！ホロックス！
HoloX! HoloX!
世界を手にするホロックス！
HoloX that will take over the world!
世界を変えてくホロックス！
HoloX that will change the world!
世界はこの手にホロックス！
The world is in our hands, HoloX!
心を解き放て
Set your heart free
ほら、どうぞどうぞ身を任せて
Here, go ahead, just let yourself go
もう逃げられない
You can't escape anymore
ほら 闇に染まれば
Look, if you're dyed in darkness
世界を塗り替えろ
Repaint the world
望めば呉れてやろう すべて
If you wish for it, I'll give it all to you
常識 破り捨てろ
Throw away your common sense
狂い倒せ 火を点けろ
Go crazy, set it on fire
ラッパッパッパラッパ
Ra-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
捨てちまえ 喰らい尽くせ
Throw it away, devour it all
ラッパッパッパラッパ
Ra-pa-pa-pa-ra-pa
機密を教えてやろう
I'll let you in on the secrets
フー！フー！
Whoo! Whoo!
というわけで、常夜リペイントでしたー！
And that was Joy-ful Paint!
イェーイ！盛り上がったかー？
Yeah! Did you guys have fun?
イェーイ！やっぱりこの曲だな！
Yeah! This is the song, after all!
ホロックスですね！
It's so HoloX!
ホロックスですよ！
Truly HoloX!
そうだね！
Right!
一番好き！一番好きな曲！
I love it most! My favorite song!
わかる！常夜リペイント一番いい！
I get it! Joy-ful Paint is the best!
何が一番好き？
What do you like most about it?
常夜、常夜、常夜...
Joy, Joy, Joy...
常夜リペイントかな！
Maybe Joy-ful Paint!
えー、やっぱ好きなんだ！
Oh, you really like it!
あの、4th Fesの思い出も含めて！
Including the memories of 4th Fes!
わかる！わかるよ！
I know! I know!
エモさがやばい！
The emotional impact is crazy!
みんなで立ったもんね、そこに！
We all stood there together!
「総員、跪け！」って言った瞬間、みんな「うわぁぁぁ！」って！
The moment we said "All hands, kneel!", everyone went "Whoaaa!"
会場揺れてたもんな！
The venue was shaking!
すごかったもんね！
It was amazing!
あれはいい思い出ですね！
That's a great memory!
覚えてる？
Do you remember?
覚えてますよ！
I remember!
そこまでは忘れないわよ！
I won't forget that far!
いやでもクロヱさんに、我々あの...伝えたいことが...
But, Chloe-san, we... have something we want to tell you...
何ですか？
What is it?
伝えたいことが、じゃあ並ぶか！
We want to tell you... okay, let's line up!
待ってこれエモいやつ？
Wait, is this one of those emotional things?
待って待って、縦に並ぶの？
Wait, wait, we're lining up vertically?
こっちこっち、クロヱそっち！
This way, this way. Chloe, stay there!
エモいやつですよね、これ！
This is an emotional one, right?!
行くぞ！クロヱちゃん！
Here we go! Chloe-chan!
最後にいいですか？
Is it okay for the last one?
行きますよ、皆さん！
Here we go, everyone!
聞いてほしい！
Listen up!
ク！
Ku!
ロ！
Ro!
エ！
E!
い！
I!
ま！
Ma!
で！
De!
あ！
A!
り！
Ri!
が！
Ga!
と！
To!
うー！！
Uuuu!!
いや誕生日のやつや！
Hey, that's the birthday thing!
誕生日のふざけのやつじゃ！
That's the birthday joke thing!
いや違う、エモい感じかと...
No, I thought it was going to be emotional...
エモくないの？
It's not emotional?
いやこれエロくないよ！
No, this isn't erotic!
エロい？
Erotic?
エロいって言った？
Did you say erotic?
やめてください！
Please stop!
ラ行にしないで！
Don't turn it into the 'R' column!
エロくない！何て聞いてんの！
It's not erotic! What were you listening to?!
いや、クロヱだからあり得るのよ！
Well, it's possible because it's Chloe!
まぁね、確かに！
Well, true!
まぁ、これがホロックスらしさですよね！
Well, this is typical HoloX!
これも思い出補正でエモくなるんですよ！
Even this will become emotional with nostalgia!
何でも今日はエモくなっちゃう！
Everything becomes emotional today!
思い出してね！
Remember this!
むしろこれぐらいのほうが嬉しいまである
It's even better this way, almost.
ありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you so much, really!
嬉しいとか自分に言い聞かせて...
Telling yourself you're happy...
みんなでシクシク「うぅぅ」言われなくていいよね！
It's better than everyone sobbing like "uuu"!
確かに！
True!
沙花叉も笑顔で出ていきたいからね！
Since Sakamata also wants to leave with a smile!
あ、いいこと言った！
Oh, well said!
まぁホロライブはあれだけど...
Well, Hololive might be like that, but...
ホロックスは関係ないから！
It doesn't matter to HoloX!
いつでもアジトに来てもらっていいから！
You can come to the hideout anytime!
さっき最後って言ったけど、アジトで歌えるからね！
I said it was the last time earlier, but we can sing at the hideout!
5人でね！
With all five of us!
できるできる！カラオケ行ける！
We can, we can! We can go to karaoke!
4th Fesのブルーレイ見てやろう！
Let's watch the 4th Fes Blu-ray!
アジトカラオケ！
Hideout karaoke!
いいじゃん！できるできる！
Sounds good! We can do it!
あの時と振りも違ってくるしね！
The choreography will be different from then, too!
そうだね！新振りになってますから！
Right! Since it's new choreography now!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
こちらこそ！
Our pleasure!
嬉しいです、こうやって見送ってもらえるというか...
I'm happy being sent off like this...
一緒に楽しいことも、辛いときも同期として頑張ってきたなって思うから
Because I feel like we worked hard as genmates through both fun and tough times.
本当に嬉しいです！ありがとうございます！
I'm really happy! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
本当にエモい。
This is really emotional.
エモいね。
It is, isn't it?
はいてないやついます、はいてないやついます。
Someone isn't wearing them, someone isn't wearing them.
ちょっと、はいてください！
Hey, please put them on!
何で... 違うもん！
Why... No, you're wrong!
何でこんな素敵な時に言わなきゃいけないの！
Why do you have to say that at such a wonderful time!
違う、違う、やっぱ輝くのはうちらじゃなくて今日クロヱがいいかなと思って。
No, no, I just thought today Chloe should be the one to shine, not us.
よこせよ、よこせよ、マジで！
Give it to me, give it to me, seriously!
ちょっとその情緒感狙わないで！
Hey, don't try to aim for that emotional vibe!
汚れなくていい、綺麗にきて、それ。
You don't need to get dirty, come out beautifully in that.
いや、本当にありがとね。もう...
No, really, thank you. I mean...
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちょっとこれからのことも、ホロックス4人が頑張ってるところ見届けていきたいので。
Since I want to continue watching over the four members of HoloX as they do their best...
またこれからも、ホロックスとしても、そしてホロライブのメンバーとしても...
From now on as well, as HoloX and as members of Hololive...
頑張ってください、応援してます。
Please do your best, I'm rooting for you.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いや、これクロヱのさ、パート取り合いだね、これね。
Man, this is gonna be a scramble for Chloe's parts, isn't it?
確かに。
That's true.
やめてよ、奪わないで！
Stop it, don't take them!
手を挙げろ、手を挙げろ！
Put your hands up, put your hands up!
でも見たい。
But I want to see it.
いや、あれ全員で自分の名前言うでしょ、クロヱのところ。
No, everyone will just say their own names in Chloe's parts.
やってみる？
Shall we try?
ラプラス・ダークネス！ 高嶺ルイ！ 博衣こより！ 沙花叉クロヱ！ 風真いろは！
Laplus Darknesss! Takane Lui! Hakui Koyori! Sakamata Chloe! Kazama Iroha!
うるさいよ！
You're so noisy!
うるさい！ 一番でかい奴、そういうパートじゃないから！
Be quiet! You with the loudest voice, that's not what that part is for!
今日は誰々のパートみたいな。
Like, "Today is so-and-so's part."
もう一日ずつさ、クロヱの声真似しながらしてね。
Every single day, please do it while imitating Chloe's voice.
やだもう！
Oh, stop it!
辞めたら好き勝手やられる、本当に。
They're really gonna do whatever they want once I leave.
だからそれを見守ってて下さい。
So please keep watching over that.
はい、はい、見守ります。
Yes, yes, we'll watch over it.
やだ、好き勝手やられて...
Geez, they're just doing whatever...
いや、でも本当にありがとうございました。
No, but really, thank you very much.
こちらこそありがとうございました。
The pleasure was ours, thank you.
お疲れ様でした。
Thank you for your hard work.
元気でね。
Take care.
元気で行く！
I'll stay healthy!
本当に今回も、あれですね、頑張ってくださいということで。
Really, this time too, please do your best.
締めに掛かる感じやめて。
Stop making it feel like we're wrapping up.
そうだよ、まだあるよ、クロヱ。
That's right, there's still more, Chloe.
クロヱまだあるよ。
Chloe still has more.
うちら5人で最後の曲！
The last song with the five of us!
悲しいこと言うな！
Don't say such sad things!
頑張るよ、最後まで頑張るよ。
I'll do my best, I'll do my best until the end.
いや、でも本当にみんなでさ、せっかくのだしせーので入ろうよ。
No, but really everyone, since it's a special song, let's start it on "Ready, go."
せーので入ろうよ。
Let's start it on "Ready, go."
お願い。
Please.
せーので歌いたいよ。
I want to sing it on "Ready, go."
いいよ、いいよ。
Alright, alright.
じゃあ歌うんですよ、いきますよ。
Well then, we're going to sing, here we go.
見てください、せーの！
Please watch, ready, go!
サマータイムレコード！
Summertime Record!
サマータイムレコード
作詞作曲：じん
Summertime Record
Lyrics/Composition: Jin
昨日も今日も晴天で 入道雲を見ていた
Yesterday and today were both clear, I was watching the thunderclouds
怠いくらいの快晴だ 終むろに目を閉じて
The weather is almost lazily fine, I slowly close my eyes
それはどうも簡単に 思い出せやしないようで
It seems that won't be remembered so easily
年を取った現状に 浸ってたんだよ
I was immersing myself in the fact that I've aged
あぁ...
Ah...
大人振った作戦で 不思議な合図立てて
With a plan to act like adults, making a strange signal
「行こうか、今日も戦争だ」 立ち向かって手を取った
"Let's go, today's another battle," we stood up and took each other's hands
理不尽なんて当然で 独りぼっち強いられて
Unreasonableness is only natural, forced to be all alone
迷った僕は憂鬱に なりそうになってさ
Lost, I was about to become melancholy
背伸びした空を分けて 滲む太陽に手を
Dividing the sky I stretched for, my hand to the blurring sun
「君のせいだ」食いしばった
"It's your fault," I gritted my teeth
孤独だったらおいでよ
If you're lonely, come here
騒がしさも思い出して 生まれた感情さえも
Remembering the noise too, even the emotions that were born
頭に浮かんでは萎んだ 幻のままかな
Those that came to mind and withered away, will they remain illusions?
秘密基地に集まって 「楽しいね」って単純な
Gathering at our secret base, saying "it's fun" was so simple
あの頃を思い出して 話をしよう
Remembering those days, let's talk
飛行機雲飛んでって 「眩しいね」って泣いていた
The vapor trails flew by, we were crying saying "it's so bright"
君はどんな顔だっけ
What kind of face did you have?
なぜか、思い出せないな
For some reason, I can't remember
痛いくらいの現実は 足早に駆け抜けた
The reality, so much that it hurt, rushed past quickly
選んだ今日は平凡で 崩れそうになる
The today I chose is so ordinary, I feel like I'm going to crumble
昨日も今日も...
Yesterday and today...
...させて　大人だって供養だ
...let us. Even for adults, it's a memorial.
今になれば　自ずと気づけた事だったんだよ
Looking back, it was something I should've realized on my own.
回る世界の彩　照れる太陽炎天下
The colors of the revolving world, the shy sun in the scorching heat.
陽炎が揺らいだ　『忘れないでさ、進もう』
The heat haze shimmered. "Don't forget, let's keep moving forward."
もどかしさになんてでも　明日を夢に見ていた
Despite the frustration, I was still dreaming of tomorrow.
戻らない先のある世界へ　僕たちで変えましょう
To a world where there's no turning back, let's change it ourselves.
思い出して、終わったって
Remember, even if it's over.
秘密基地も、冒険も
The secret base, the adventures,
あの日に迷い込んだ　話の事も
And the stories we strayed into that day.
独りぼっちが集まった　子供たちの作戦が
The mission of the children, where the lonely souls gathered,
また廻り出した
Has begun to turn once again.
また、どこかで。
Again, somewhere.
涼風が吹き抜けた　夏空は透明だ
A cool breeze blew through; the summer sky is transparent.
涙を吸い込んで　『さよなら』しよう
Absorb the tears, and let's say "Goodbye."
秘密基地に集まって　笑い合った夏の日に
On those summer days we gathered at the base and laughed together,
またどこかで思い出した　出会えるかな、なんて事
I remembered somewhere... "I wonder if we'll meet again."
というわけで、ゲストパート見ていただいてありがとうございました！
And so, thank you all for watching the guest segment!
あのですね、収録時期が、あのホロックスライブより前なんですよ。
Well, you see, the recording period was actually before the HoloX Live.
見てて分かったと思うんですけど、言ってる事がね...
I think you could tell from watching, but the things I was saying...
人格変わっちゃったんか？っていうくらい全然違うんですけど、
It's so different, you might wonder if my personality changed.
『笑って別れようイェーイ！』みたいな感じになってるんですけど、だいぶ前に撮ったものにして、
I'm all like "Let's say goodbye with a smile, yay!" because it was filmed quite a while ago.
なのでね、結局泣いちゃったっていうｗ　みんな泣いちゃったってやつなんですけど。
So, well, I ended up crying in the end lol. We all ended up crying.
でもなんかホロックスらしい一面がこうやってね、また見れて良かったなと思います。ありがとうございます。
But I'm glad we could see that HoloX-like side of us again. Thank you.
そしてゲストについてなんですけど、もう結構序盤から分かってた子いたんですよ、コメントで。
And about the guests, some people in the comments figured it out quite early on.
実は今回、同期のメンバーでゲストに来ていただきました。
Actually, this time, I had my genmates come as guests.
すいせい先輩と、富士急だったりとか、ぺこら先輩とハンバーガーだったり、
Suisei-senpai at Fuji-Q, Pekora-senpai with hamburgers,
かなけんでお料理、
Cooking with Shiraken,
こんこよとは謎解きリアル脱出っすね、
The riddle-solving real escape game with Konkoyo,
そしてシオン先輩とはバンジージャンプと静岡。
And bungee jumping in Shizuoka with Shion-senpai.
もしね、動画まだ見てない子いたら、よかったら見てみてはいかがでしょうか。
If any of you haven't seen those videos yet, please do check them out.
ちょっといろんな思い出を作ってきたので。
We made quite a few memories together.
そして、いよいよですね、次の曲がラストになってしまいます。
And now, finally, the next song will be the last one.
最後の曲はせっかくなので、あのステージで歌いたいと思います。
For the final song, since it's special, I'd like to sing it on *that* stage.
じゃあ、移動しますので、ちょっと待っててねー！
Alright, I'll be moving over there, so please wait a moment!
Now Loading
というわけでやってきました、水族館ステージです！いぇーい！
So here we are, at the Aquarium Stage! Yay!
えーちょっとね、3Dお披露目の時にこのステージを使ったこともあって、
Um, well, since I used this stage during my 3D showcase,
皆さん思い出が深いんじゃないかなと思うので、このステージで最後は曲を歌いたいと思います。
I think everyone has deep memories of it, so I'd like to sing the last song on this stage.
の前に、の前に...
But before that, before that...
あのですね、えーこの後22時30分から、
Well, um, starting from 22:30 later tonight,
沙花叉が作詞作曲したオリ曲の『光あれ』がプレミア公開になります。
the original song I wrote and composed, "Hikari Are," will have its premiere.
そちらも良かったら見てみてください。この飼育員さんたちと過ごした3年、
Please check that out too if you'd like. I made it with feelings of gratitude
約3年間の、えー感謝の気持ちや色々な思いを込めて作ったので、ぜひ見ていただけると嬉しいです。
and various emotions from the 3 years, about 3 years, I spent with you Seekers, so I'd be happy if you'd watch it.
そして、えーholoXでの歌ってみたが、なんと23時頃に上がりますので、
And, um, a cover song by holoX will be uploaded around 23:00,
そちらもよろしくお願いします。
so please look forward to that as well.
はい。
Yes.
で、もう一個あるんです。
And, there's one more thing.
これじゃなくてですね、ちょっと、まあ、恥ずかしい、んですけど...
Not about this, but... it's a bit, well, embarrassing...
お、え、何？
Oh, eh, what?
え、えー！？
Eh, eee!?
何！？
What!?
ねえ、やめてよそういうの！
Hey, stop that kind of thing!
サプライズでマネちゃんからお手紙もらっちゃった...
I got a surprise letter from Mane-chan...
もうやだよー！ねー！
I don't like this anymore! Hey!
泣かないできたじゃんここまで！
I've made it this far without crying!
ずるいよー！
That's not fair!
じゃあちょっと、読みたいと思います。
Well, I'd like to read it.
「クロヱさん、お疲れ様です。」
"Chloe-san, thank you for your hard work."
「少し照れくさいですが、初めて手紙書いちゃいますね。」
"It's a bit embarrassing, but I'm writing a letter for the first time."
「まだまだ未熟なマネージャーの私に、いつでも優しく接してくれてありがとうございました。」
"Thank you for always being kind to me, an inexperienced manager."
いや、もう、こっち、本当にこちらこそですけどね。
No, really, I should be the one saying that.
「正直楽しいことばかりではなく、大変なこともたくさんあって、
"To be honest, it wasn't all fun; there were many difficult things,
どうしたらいいのかと頭を悩ませたこともありました。」
and there were times when I worried about what to do."
「でもクロヱさんとだから大変なことは半分に、
"But I believe that because it was with you, Chloe-san,
楽しいことは倍に、この3年間を乗り切れたと思ってます。」
the hard times were halved and the fun times were doubled, allowing us to get through these three years."
「気づいたら、家の中がクロヱさんのグッズでいっぱいで、
"Before I knew it, my house was full of your merch,
仕事に行く時は娘ちゃんが『クロヱちゃんに会いにいってくるの？』と聞いてくるようになりました。」
and when I go to work, my daughter started asking, 'Are you going to see Chloe-chan?'"
「嬉しい反面、今後はなんて答えればいいのか悩んじゃいますね。」
"While I'm happy, I'm worried about how to answer from now on."
「この3年間、ダンスレッスンやボイトレ、収録などのお仕事を
"During these past three years, I've watched you from the closest distance
真面目に一生懸命頑張っている姿を一番近くで見させていただきました。」
as you worked seriously and hard on dance lessons, vocal training, and recordings."
「活動に関して熱い思いを抱いてるクロヱさんに追いつこうと必死で、
"I was desperate to catch up with you, Chloe-san, as you have such a strong passion for your activities,
クロヱさんの期待に応えられるよう頑張っていましたが、並んで仕事ができていたでしょうか。」
and I worked hard to meet your expectations, but I wonder if I was able to work alongside you."
うう...
Uuu...
当たり前じゃん。
Of course you were.
当たり前すぎる。むしろ、むしろ助けられてためっちゃ。
It's more than obvious. Rather, I was the one who was helped so much.
全然、全然逆だけどな。
It's completely the opposite.
「正直とても不安でした。本当はもっともっと色々なことを教えていただきたかったです。」
"To be honest, I was very anxious. I really wanted to be taught much more by you."
「言葉選びのセンス、飼育員さんとの関わり方など、尊敬しかないけれど、
"Your sense of word choice, the way you interact with the Seekers, and so on...
クロヱさんのマネージャーになれて幸せでした。」
I have nothing but respect, and I was happy to be your manager."
「記念配信で名取さんと堂々と歌い上げてるクロヱさんを間近で見させていただき、
"I watched you from up close as you sang proudly with Natori-san in your anniversary stream,
そのかっこいい姿、忘れません。」
and I will never forget how cool you looked."
「本当にお疲れ様でした。そして見たことない景色をたくさん見せていただき、
"Thank you so much for your hard work. And thank you for showing me many sights
ありがとうございました。これからも応援してます。マネちゃんより。」
I had never seen before. I'll continue to support you. From Mane-chan."
ねー、もう、ずるー...
Hey, seriously, that's unfair...
あれ？終わって...
Huh? It's finished...
あれ？ちょっと待って。あれ？
Huh? Wait a minute. Huh?
今さ、泣いちゃう... もう本当に、もう、やめてーって思ったのにさ、PSがある。
I'm about to cry now... I really thought, "stop it already," but there's a P.S.
PS。最後の最後の今日もとても...
P.S. On this very last day, you're also very...
大切なものを忘れてきて...
Forgetting something important...
...妹ちゃんを召喚したのも良い思い出として、大切に心にしまっておき...
...and summoning my little sister will be a good memory I'll cherish in my heart...
お体に、お気を付けて、ゆっくり休んでくださいませ。
Please take care of yourself and get some rest.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、もう、本当に、すみませんでした。
Man, I'm really, really sorry.
もう一回、本当、いっぱい教えてくれてるんですけどね、すぐ忘れちゃう。
Once more... they taught me so much, but I forget it all instantly.
いや、もうね、ずるいよ。
Man, that's not fair.
どうすんの、ここでさ、もう泣きそうだよ本当に、もうやだ...
What am I supposed to do? I'm about to cry. This is too much...
ありがとうございました。本当に、楽しかったです。
Thank you so much. It was truly fun.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ということで、えー、サプライズすぎて、訳分からなくなってますが...
So, uh, it's such a big surprise that I'm kind of lost, but...
もう泣いちゃったよ。この後さ、歌うのに、もうやめてください本当に...
I'm already crying. I have to sing after this, please stop it already...
ということで、マネちゃんからのサプライズのお手紙、ありがとうございました。
Anyway, thank you for the surprise letter from my manager.
坂又も、飼育員さんに、お手紙書いてきたんです。
I've also written a letter for all the keepers.
読んでいいですか？
May I read it?
いきます。
Here I go.
飼育員さんへ。
To my keepers.
ホロライブでは短く、世間では、中学生が高校生になってしまうような、
It was a short time in Hololive, but long enough for a junior high student to enter high school.
長いような、短いような、とても濃い時間を一緒に過ごしてくれて、ありがとうございました。
Thank you for spending such a long, yet short, and very intense time with me.
初配信ではポンだらけで、ほぼアドリブで話していたり、
My debut was full of blunders, and I mostly spoke ad-lib...
ライブでも生歌に緊張しすぎて、声が震えたり、
I'd get so nervous singing live that my voice would shake...
ヨダレで溺れたり、笑っちゃうようなことも、
I even choked on my own spit. There were funny moments...
悔しいことも、いっぱいあったね。
And many frustrating times too, weren't there?
体を壊して、心配をかけていくことが増えていき、
My health declined, and I started worrying you more and more.
坂又自身すごく悩んだし、申し訳なさから一人で泣いている時もありました。
I struggled a lot and would sometimes cry alone out of guilt.
それでも、飼育員さんと過ごす日々の中で、少しずつ成長していったり、
Even so, through the days spent with my keepers, I gradually grew.
自分を大切にしようという気持ちが強くなってきて、
My desire to cherish myself grew stronger.
活動だけではない坂又の人生にとって、大きないい変化が、たくさん起こりました。
Many major positive changes happened, not just in my activities, but in my life.
それは、偶然起きたものではなくて、飼育員さんがいつも優しく、愛を届け続けてくれたから、
This didn't happen by chance. It's because my keepers were always kind and kept sending me love.
この人たちにもっと笑っていてほしい、
I wanted to see these people smile more.
こんな素敵な人たちの、大切なものである坂又が、坂又自身を大切にしなきゃだめだと思ったからだよ。
I realized that since I'm someone precious to such wonderful people, I must cherish myself.
気づかせてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for making me realize that.
ホロライブで過ごして学んだことや思い出は、ずっと坂又の中に残ります。
The things I learned and the memories I made in Hololive will stay with me forever.
飼育員さんへの気持ちも、信頼も、絆も、何も変わることはありません。
My feelings for my keepers, my trust, and our bond will never change.
大切にこの先も歩んでいくので、この旅立ちを、見守ってください。
I'll continue walking forward with care, so please watch over my new journey.
本当に、3年間、ありがとうございました。
Thank you truly for these three years.
大好きだよ。
I love you all.
またどこかで。
See you again somewhere.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
あー、もう、気持ちぐちゃぐちゃ...
Oh man, my emotions are all over the place...
気持ちぐちゃぐちゃなんですが、
I'm a mess of emotions, but...
次が、本当に、最後の曲です。
The next one is truly the last song.
みんな、おう、ありがとね。
Everyone, thank you so much.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
スタッフさんたちも、ありがとうございました。
Thanks to the staff as well.
それでは、聴いてください。
Now, please listen.
海の幽霊。
Spirits of the Sea.
開け放たれた　この部屋には　誰もいない
In this room left wide open, there is no one
潮風の匂い　染み付いた　椅子が一つ
A single chair, stained with the scent of the sea breeze
海の幽霊
Spirits of the Sea
あなたがどこかで迷わないように
So you don't get lost somewhere,
開けておくよ
I'll leave it open.
軋む戸を叩いて
Knock on the creaking door.
何から話せばいいのか
What should I talk about first?
分からなくなる
I stop knowing...
かな
...I wonder.
星が降る夜にあなたに会えた
I met you on a night when stars were falling.
あの夜を忘れはしない
I will never forget that night.
大切なことは言葉にならない
Important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on that summer day.
思いがけず
Unexpectedly,
光るのは海の幽霊
The ones shining are the spirits of the sea.
茹だる夏の夕に小梢が
On a sweltering summer evening, the treetops
船を見送る
watch the ship sail away.
いくつかの歌を囁く
Whispering a few songs,
花を散らして
scattering flowers.
あなたがどこかで笑う
You laugh somewhere,
声が聞こえる
I hear your voice.
熱い頬の手触り
The touch of hot cheeks.
ねじれた道を進んだら
If I go down the twisted path,
そのまぶたが
those eyelids
開く
will open.
離れ離れてもときめくもの
Even if we're apart, there's something that flutters.
叫ぼう今は幸せと
Let's shout out now that we're happy.
大切なことは言葉にならない
Important things cannot be put into words.
跳ねる光に溶かして
Melting into the bouncing light.
星が降る夜にあなたに会えた
I met you on a night when stars were falling.
あの時を忘れはしない
I will never forget that moment.
大切なことは言葉にならない
Important things cannot be put into words.
夏の日に起きたすべて
Everything that happened on that summer day.
思いがけず
Unexpectedly,
光るのは海の幽霊
The ones shining are the spirits of the sea.
風薫る砂浜で
On the wind-scented beach,
また会いましょう
Let's meet again.
出演
Cast
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
AZKi
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
紫咲シオン
Murasaki Shion
兎田ぺこら
Usada Pekora
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
ラプラス・ダークネス
La+ Darknesss
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
Special Thanks
飼育員
Keepers (Fans)
疲れたー
I'm so tired!
疲れたねー。お疲れー。
We're tired, aren't we? Good job.
良かったよー。ありがとう。いいライブだったよ。
It was great. Thank you. It was a good live.
歌上手いじゃん。
You're a really good singer.
今更？今更？
You're saying that now? Now?
てか、お腹空いたんですけど。
Anyway, I'm starving.
お腹空いたねー。
I'm hungry too.
ルイさんお腹空きましたよー。
Lui-san, we're hungry!
えっ、今日夕飯？
Eh, dinner today?
今日はー、ちょっと作りたくない...
Today... I don't really want to cook...
えー？なんでー？お腹空いたー！
Eh? Why not? I'm hungry!
てことはー、焼肉？
Which means... yakiniku?
焼肉！焼肉！
Yakiniku! Yakiniku!
誰がお金出すの？
Who's paying?
サス！サス！サス！サス！
Lui! Lui! Lui! Lui!
じゃあいつもの焼肉屋行きますか。
Then shall we go to the usual place?
行こう行こう！あそこだよ！
Let's go! That's the place!
食べ放題！食べ放題だ！
All-you-can-eat! It's all-you-can-eat!
ラプラスおごりね。
Laplus, it's your treat.
やだ！
No way!
あ、忘れてました！
Ah, I forgot something!
えー！？早く！財布！財布！
Eh!? Hurry up! Wallet! Wallet!
財布じゃないよ！
It's not the wallet!
ラプラス財布持ってくれないよ。
Laplus won't carry the wallet for you.
行ってくるね！
I'll be right back!
オッケー。
Okay.
まだー？早くしてよー！
Not yet? Hurry up!
待ってよー！お腹空いたよー！
Wait for me! I'm hungry!
行くから待って！
I'm coming, so wait!
早く！早く！
Hurry! Hurry!
焼肉！焼肉！
Yakiniku! Yakiniku!
ありがとう
Thank you